ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError.
ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError.
You'll encounter this error if your code\hchanges a value after change detection\hhas been run and the view has been built.\h
如果你的代码在运行完变更检测 并构建好视图之后又修改了某个值，就会遇到本错误
You'll only see this error in development\h because Angular runs an additional change\h\h
你只会在开发模式下看到本错误 因为 Angular 会运行一次额外的
detection check to catch errors like\h this that can cause erratic UI behavior.\h
变更检测来捕获此类错误 此类错误会导致古怪的 UI 行为
The extra check ensures the app is stable and that\h all data updates have been reflected in the views.\h
这次额外的检查可以确保应用已进入稳定态 对数据的所有更新都已经反映到了视图上
There are a variety of reasons the view might\h be left in an inconsistent state,
有很多原因都可能导致视图处于不一致状态
such as code\hthat updates the view during the AfterViewInit\h lifecycle hook or when change detection triggers\h\h
比如某些代码在 AfterViewInit 钩子中更新了视图 或变更检测触发器自身进入了无限循环
itself in an infinite loop, like a method that\h returns a different value each time,
比如某个被绑定的方法每次都返回不同的值
or a child\hcomponent that changes the bindings on its parent.
或者某个子组件修改了其父组件/父指令上的绑定
Let's start by looking at a simple reproduction\hand solution.
我们来看一个简单的问题复现及其解决方案
Then, we'll take a more detailed\h look at Angular's change detection to understand\h\h
然后，我们仔细看一下 Angular 的变更检测，以便理解
why this error happens and why it's important. Here in the app component template we're using\h\h
为什么会发生本错误，以及它为何如此重要 这里是我们正在使用的 AppComponent 模板
the ngIf directive with a loading boolean. In the model, or our component type script,\h\h
ngIf 指令带有一个布尔值 loading 在模型（也就是我们的组件 TypeScript 代码）中
we give it a default value of true. Then, using\h the AfterViewInit lifecycle hook we flip the\h\h
我们给了它一个默认值 true 然后，在 AfterViewInit 钩子中
value to false when it's done loading. But when we run this code we see\h\h
当加载完成时，我们把它的值翻转为 false 但是当我们运行此代码时，会看到报错：
ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError:\h Previous value: false, Current value: true.\h
ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError: Previous value: false, Current value: true.
Now in a more complex app it might not be\h clear where this error originates from,\h\h
在更复杂的应用中，错误的源头可能没这么清晰
but you can always assume that it has\h something to do with a binding in the template.\h
但是你始终可以假设，它对模板中的绑定做了点什么
In the stack trace you'll find a link to the\h source map for the component template that\h\h
在调用栈追踪中，你会发现一个链接 它指向导致本错误的组件模板的源码映射
caused the error and it takes us directly\h to the line of code that caused the issue,\h\h
并且它直接把我们带到了导致此问题的代码行
which is our ngIf binding to the loading boolean. What the error is trying to tell us is that\h\h
也就是我们绑定到 loading 属性的 ngIf 语句 本错误在试图告诉我们
the loading value has changed after the change\h detection cycle has completed, but what exactly\h\h
这个 loading 属性的值在变更检测循环完成之后发生了变化
is wrong with our code in this case? The short answer is that we're using\h\h
但是在这个例子中我们的代码到底错在哪里呢？ 简短的答案是我们正在使用错误的
the wrong lifecycle hook. If we move our code from\h\h
生命周期钩子 如果我们把代码从
AfterViewInit to OnInit the error goes\h away and everything works perfectly.\h
AfterViewInit 移到 OnInit 中，本错误就消失了 这些就恢复正常了
In other words, if you find yourself updating\h values in AfterViewInit there's a good chance\h\h
换句话说，如果你发现自己正在 AfterViewInit 中修改值
that a simple refactor to OnInit or the\h component constructor will fix the issue.\h
就可以简单地把它移到 OnInit 或组件构造函数中来修复它
Okay, at this point we know we used the wrong\h lifecycle hook and we can fix it by refactoring,\h\h
现在，我们已经明白使用了错误的生命周期钩子 并且可以通过重构来修复它
but to really understand why let's do a quick\h review of how change detection works in Angular.\h
但要想真正理解其原因，我们就要快速回顾一下 Angular 中变更检测的工作原理
The goal of change detection is to\h keep the model, your typescript code,\h\h
变更检测的目标，是让模型（TypeScript 代码）与
in sync with the template, your html. And it does so by looking for data\h\h
模板（HTML）保持同步。 它实现这一点的方式，是通过
changes in the component tree from top to bottom. First it checks the parent, then the first child,\h\h
在组件树中自顶向下查找数据变更 首先它检查父组件，然后是子组件
second child and so on, but if we update a\h binding on the parent after it has already\h\h
然后是二级子组件，以此类推。但是如果我们在 父组件完成变更检查之后再修改某个绑定
been checked Angular will throw the error. Now what we have here is a simplified\h\h
Angular 就会抛出本错误 现在，我们有了一个简化的
breakdown of Angular's life cycle, or the steps\h it performs when a component is first initialized.\h
Angular 生命周期分解图，
First it updates the bindings like\h the ngIf directive in the template.\h
首先它像此模板中的 ngIf 指令一样修改这些绑定
Then it runs the OnInit lifecycle\h hook, updates the DOM, then runs\h\h
然后，它运行 OnInit 生命周期钩子 修改 DOM，然后运行子组件的变更检测
change detection for the child component. Notice how the final step is AfterViewInit,\h\h
要注意，这里的最后一步是 AfterViewInit
and more importantly that it\h runs after change detection.\h
更重要的是它运行在变更检测之后
Basically any code that runs here\h should not attempt to update the view\h\h
基本上，这里运行的所有代码 都不应该尝试更新其视图
and that was the root of the problem in this case. Refactoring to OnInit works great for initial\h\h
这就是本例子中问题的根源 把它重构到 OnInit 中对于初始值是非常合适的
values, but if that doesn't fix the issue there\h are a few other ways you may have encountered\h\h
但是如果这没能修复本错误 那可能是因为其它原因导致了本错误
this error, along with additional ways to fix it. In the component here, we're using ViewChild to\h\h
那就要用其它方式来修复它 在此组件中，我们正在用 ViewChild 从 DOM 树中捕获某个元素
grab an element from the DOM, but this\h element won't be available until the\h\h
但是此元素在调用完 AfterViewInit 钩子之前是不可用的
AfterViewInit lifecycle hook is called. But what if we can't update the state of\h\h
但是我们却不能在得到此 ViewChild 元素之前
the component until after we\h have the ViewChild element?\h
更新组件的状态，这下该怎么办呢？
If we can't refactor to ngOnInit,\h we have a couple of other options.\h
如果我们不能重构到 ngOnInit 中 我们还有另外一些选择
An approach you'll often see on StackOverflow\h answers is to make the update asynchronous.\h
你在 StackOverflow 答案中经常看到的方法之一 就是进行异步更新
When we make the update async, it'll be\h picked up on the next change detection\h\h
当我们进行异步更新时，它会推到下一次变更检测周期中进行
check and prevent the error from occurring. We can make it asynchronous by wrapping it in\h\h
这样就会防止发生错误 我们可以把它包裹进一个延迟为 0 的 setTimeout 中
a set timeout with a delay of zero. That'll put\h the update in the next macro task queue of the\h\h
来把它变成异步的。 这样就会把此更新推到 JavaScript 事件循环的下一个宏任务队列中
Javascript event loop. Alternatively we can use\h a promise that resolves immediately, then run the\h\h
另外，我可以还可以使用一个立即解析的 Promise，然后在其
update in its callback. This code will achieve the\h same result, the only subtle difference is that\h\h
回调中运行此更新。这段代码会达到同样的效果 但是有一些微妙的差异：
it runs on the micro task queue before the end of\h the current iteration in the browser's event loop.\h
它会运行在浏览器事件循环的当前迭代结束前的 微任务队列中
Making the update asynchronous can\h work, however it's very implicit\h\h
进行异步更新可以奏效，但是它非常隐晦
and should really only be used as a last resort. It's not clear why we make this code asynchronous\h\h
只应该把它作为最后的应急措施 它无法说清楚为什么我们要写这段异步代码
unless you understand the nuances of Angular\h change detection and the browser's event loop.\h
除非你能理解 Angular 变更检测和浏览器事件循环中的 某些细微差异
Luckily Angular provides us with a more direct\h and explicit way to trigger change detection.\h
幸运的是，Angular 为我们提供了另一种 更直接、更明显的方式来触发变更检测
We can manually trigger it by injecting the change\h detector ref in the constructor of the component.\h
我们可以通过在组件的构造函数中注入 ChangeDetectorRef 来手动触发它
We can then use it to manually run change\h detection by calling the detect changes method.\h
然后我们就可以调用 detectChanges() 方法 来手动运行变更检测
This will tell Angular to check the view and\h its children, in which case it will notice\h\h
这会要求 Angular 检查此视图及其子视图 在这个例子中，这会通知它们
that our loading state has changed, giving\h us yet another way to address the error.\h
我们的 loading 状态已经变了 这样就给了我们另一种方式以解决本错误
Now an entirely different way you might encounter\h this error is when you have a method, usually a\h\h
你还可能以一种完全不同的方式遇到本错误 如果你有一个方法（通常是一个 getter）
getter, that doesn't return a predictable value,\h which can cause an infinite change detection loop.\h
该方法会返回不可预测的值 这样就会导致变更检测进入无限循环
Take for example this getter in our\h component that returns a random number.\h
例如，我们组件中的这个 getter 方法会返回随机数
If we try to use this value in the\h template, Angular will get a different\h\h
如果我们试图在模板中使用这个值 那么每当 Angular 进行变更检测时
value each time it's checked. The solution in this case\h\h
都会得到一个不同的值 这种情况下的解决方案是
is to make the method return a consistent\h value based on the state of the component.\h
让该方法基于当前组件的状态返回一个确定的值
In other words getters should be derived\h directly from the component state and\h\h
换句话说，各种 getter 都应该是从组件状态衍生出来的
not values that change constantly\h like timestamps or random numbers.\h
而不能是那些不断变化的值，如时间戳或随机数
Now let's take a look at one more example, where\h we have both a parent and child component at play.\h
现在，我们来看一个更复杂的例子 这个例子中我们同时有父组件和子组件
The app component the parent contains the\h loading state just like our previous examples,\h\h
父组件 AppComponent 包含 loading 状态 就像以前的例子中一样
but instead of running the update from the\h parent component, we'll make it happen from\h\h
但是我们不在父组件中进行修改，而是改为
a child component with a custom event. In the item component, the child,\h\h
从子组件中使用自定义事件进行修改 在子组件 ItemComponent 中
we're using the @Output decorator to create\h a custom event along with an event emitter.\h
我们使用 @Output 装饰器和 EventEmitter 来创建一个自定义事件
Then during ngOnInit we'll go ahead and\h emit the event with a value of true.\h
接着，在 ngOnInit 期间，我们以 true 值发出一个事件
Then back in the app component template we'll\h go ahead and declare the item component.\h
然后，回到 AppComponent 的模板中 我们继续并声明 ItemComponent
When it fires, we'll set\h the loading value to false.\h
当自定义事件触发时 我们把 loading 值设置为 false
The end result is a situation where we have a\h child component updating the parent after change\h\h
最终的结果是我们有一个子组件 它在父组件的变更检测执行完之后修改了父组件
detection has already run on the parent,\h and once again that produces the error.\h
这时候就会发生本错误
A potential solution in this case would be to\h move the loading state into the child component\h\h
这个例子的潜在解决方案之一 是把 loading 状态移到子组件中
and if that's not possible you might consider\h moving this state to a shared service where it\h\h
如果这样行不通，你可以考虑 把此状态移到一个共享服务中
can be injected in multiple components.
而该服务可以注入到多个组件中
Let's finish up by doing a quick recap.\h
在结束之前，我们复述一下重点
The ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError\h occurs because a value in the template has been\h\h
出现 ExpressionChangedAfterItHasBeenCheckedError 是因为模板中的某个值
updated after change detection has finished. Debug it by first finding\h\h
在变更检测完成之后又被修改了 先找到在调用栈追踪中给出的模板来排错
the template in the stack trace. From there you can analyze your code to determine\h\h
从那里，你可以分析代码来决定到底是
where the value is being updated and use one of\h the methods covered in this video to address it,\h\h
哪个值被修改了，并且使用本视频中涵盖的方法之一来解决它
such as refactoring to the OnInit lifecycle\h hook, using change detector ref manually,\h\h
比如把它重构到 OnInit 钩子中、 手动使用 ChangeDetectorRef、
making getters item potent, or making\h your updates async as a last resort.\h
让 getter 返回确定的值 或者把修改变成异步的，作为最后的应急手段
Refer to the Angular documentation\h for additional details and examples.
参考 Angular 官方文档，以了解更多详情和范例。